{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is a type of error associated with digital-to-analog converters (DACs)?", "opta": "nonmonotonic error", "optb": "incorrect output codes", "optc": "offset error", "optd": "nonmonotonic and offset error", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit R/2R digital-to-analog (DAC) converter has a reference of 5 volts. What is the analog output for the input code 0101.", "opta": "0.3125 V", "optb": "3.125 V", "optc": "0.78125 V", "optd": "\u20133.125 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted digital-to-analog converter has an input resistor of 100 k. If the resistor is connected to a 5 V source, the current through the resistor is:", "opta": "50 A", "optb": "5 mA", "optc": "500 A", "optd": "50 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resolution of a digital-to-analog converter (DAC)?", "opta": "It is the comparison between the actual output of the converter and its expected output.", "optb": "It is the deviation between the ideal straight-line output and the actual output of the converter.", "optc": "It is the smallest analog output change that can occur as a result of an increment in the digital input.", "optd": "It is its ability to resolve between forward and reverse steps when sequenced over its entire range.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The practical use of binary-weighted digital-to-analog converters is limited to:", "opta": "R/2R ladder D/A converters", "optb": "4-bit D/A converters", "optc": "8-bit D/A converters", "optd": "op-amp comparators", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference between analog voltage represented by two adjacent digital codes, or the analog step size, is the:", "opta": "quantization", "optb": "accuracy", "optc": "resolution", "optd": "monotonicity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary disadvantage of the flash analog-to digital converter (ADC) is that:", "opta": "it requires the input voltage to be applied to the inputs simultaneously", "optb": "a long conversion time is required", "optc": "a large number of output lines is required to simultaneously decode the input voltage", "optd": "a large number of comparators is required to represent a reasonable sized binary number", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary-weighted digital-to-analog converter has a feedback resistor, Rf, of 12 k. If 50 A of current is through the resistor, the voltage out of the circuit is:", "opta": "0.6 V", "optb": "\u20130.6 V", "optc": "0.1 V", "optd": "\u20130.1 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the major advantage of the R/2R ladder digital-to-analog (DAC), as compared to a binary-weighted digital-to-analog DAC converter?", "opta": "It only uses two different resistor values.", "optb": "It has fewer parts for the same number of inputs.", "optc": "Its operation is much easier to analyze.", "optd": "The virtual ground is eliminated and the circuit is therefore easier to understand and troubleshoot.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The resolution of a 0\u20135 V 6-bit digital-to-analog converter (DAC) is:", "opta": "63%", "optb": "64%", "optc": "1.56%", "optd": "15.6%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a flash analog-to-digital converter, the output of each comparator is connected to an input of a:", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "priority encoder", "optc": "multiplexer", "optd": "demultiplexer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an analog-to-digital (ADC) conversion error?", "opta": "differential nonlinearity", "optb": "missing code", "optc": "incorrect code", "optd": "offset", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sample-and-hold circuits in analog-to digital converters (ADCs) are designed to:", "opta": "sample and hold the output of the binary counter during the conversion process", "optb": "stabilize the comparator's threshold voltage during the conversion process", "optc": "stabilize the input analog signal during the conversion process", "optd": "sample and hold the D/A converter staircase waveform during the conversion process", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}